I feel bad for doing that to Iroha.
≪(葉山)いろはには
悪いことしたな
If you're going to feel guilty,
you shouldn't have rejected her.
(比企谷)罪悪感持つくらいなら
フラなきゃよかったろ
It doesn't work that way.
(葉山)無理だよ 分かってるくせに
そういうことを言うのは
And you know that. It's pretty mean
of you to put me in that position.
性格悪いな
まあな
I guess.
いろはの気持ちは素直に嬉しい
でも違うんだ
I'm honestly happy Iroha feels that way,
but that's not what it is.
それは たぶん俺じゃなくて…
I don't think it's really me...
You're really amazing,
君はすごいな そうやって
周りの人間を変えていく
the way you change everyone around you.
Huh? Where's this coming from?
はあ？ 何だよ急に
ははッ 違うよ 言っただろ
Don't get me wrong.
Remember what I told you?
俺は君が思っているほど
いいヤツじゃない
I'm not the nice guy you think I am.
(ため息をつく葉山)
君をほめるのは 俺のためだ
I'm complimenting you for my own sake.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ](ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)間もなく海浜幕張
The train will soon arrive at
Kaihin-Makuhari. Kaihin-Makuhari.
(雪乃)では 私達は次で
Well, the next stop is ours.
Yeah.
一色 俺も次だけど
お前 駅どこだ？
Isshiki, I'm getting off, too.
Which station are you—
Senpai, my bag's really heavy.
(いろは)先輩 荷物超重いです
Yeah, that might be better.
(結衣)うん その方がいいかもね
はあ～ ダメでしたね
That didn't work.
いや お前 今言っても
ダメなことくらい分かってたろ
You shouldn't need to say that now.
You knew it wouldn't.
だって
しょうがないじゃないですか
Well, what was I supposed to do?
盛り上がっちゃったんだから
意外だな
I got all excited...
That surprised me.
お前は そういう場の雰囲気とかに
振り回されないヤツだと思ってた
I thought you weren't the type to
get caught up in what's going on around you.
私も意外でした
I was surprised, too.
もっと冷めてるんだと
思ってました
I was expecting more indifference.
Huh? I thought you were trying
to look like a love-struck fool,
ああ お前 恋愛脳に見せかけて
結構クレバーっていうか…
but were actually pretty clever...
Not from me. From you.
私じゃなくて 先輩の話です
はッ？
Huh?
あんなの見せられたら
心動いちゃいますよ
Of course I'd be moved after seeing that.
Seeing what?
何が？
私も
I'm starting to want the real thing, too.
本物がほしくなったんです
うッ 聞いてたのかよ…
You were listening?
声 普通にもれてましたよ
Your voice was perfectly audible through the door.
忘れてくれ
忘れませんよ
Forget about that.
I won't.
忘れられません
I can't forget it.
だから今日
踏み出そうと思ったんです
That's why I tried to take a step forward today.
Well, um, you know...
その 何… 気にすんなよ
Don't let it get to you.
お前が悪いわけじゃないし
It's not your fault or anything.
はッ 何ですか傷心に付け込んで
口説いてるんですか
What is this? Are you taking advantage of my heartbreak to hit on me?
ごめんなさい まだ無理です
ちげえよ
I'm sorry. I still can't.
No, I'm not.
Besides, it's not over yet!
ていうか まだ終わってませんし
むしろこれこそ
葉山先輩への有効な攻め方です
In fact, this is the most effective way to approach Hayama-senpai!
みんな私に同情するし
Everyone will sympathize with me,
周囲も遠慮するじゃないですか
お おう
and other girls won't go near him!
O-Okay...
And you know what else?
それにあと あれです フッた
相手のことって気にしますよね➡
It'll make people curious about the girl he rejected.
かわいそうだって
思うじゃないですか➡
People will feel sorry for me!
だから この敗北は布石です
So this defeat is part of the overall strategy.
次を有効に進めるため…
To make the next phase
だから その 頑張らないと…
proceed... effectively...
すごいな お前
先輩のせいですからね
You're really something.
It's your fault this happened to me, you know.
私がこうなったの
いや 会長の件はそうだけど
他のは…
Well, the student council president thing is, but the rest...
責任とってくださいね
You'd better take responsibility.
へへッ
♬～
So, um, why did you call us all here?
えっと これ集められた理由って
何ですかね～
To confirm our objective and discuss the future.
方針の確認と今後について だな
Okay...
はあ…
現状の案は ぶっちゃけ無理だ
The plan currently in place is, frankly, impossible.
Even if we pull it off, only a small part will be successful.
実現できても あの中の一部分
For all the ideas they threw out,
it'll end up being a pretty dull event.
打ち出した看板のわりに
結構しょぼいイベントになる
そうならないために
どうすればいいと思う？
What do you think we should do to prevent that?
Uh... I don't know...
はあ 分かりませんけど
問題は あの会議にある
The problem lies in those meetings.
We've pulled a lot of opinions together,
意見はまとめるが
その実 誰も決定は下してない
but no one has made any actual decisions.
だから そういう
なれ合いを排除した
So let's have a proper meeting, with none of the colluding.
ちゃんとした会議をしよう
We'll oppose, confront, and deny proposals.
反対も対立も否定もする
We'll make it clear which ideas have won.
勝ち負けをきっちりつける
そういう会議を
That kind of meeting.
えっと どうですかね？
(副会長)俺は…
Uh... What do you think?
I think... it's better if we don't make waves.
波風立てない方がいいと思う
このタイミングで対案出すのは
ちょっと難しいと思うし
And I think it'll be difficult to bring up counter-proposals at this point.
That's true...
ですよね～ でもやります
(一同)えッ？
But we'll do it.
私的にしょぼいのって
やっぱりちょっと嫌かな～って
I personally don't want this event to be dull.
Mihama
Library
Takasu
Community
Center
そうかもですけど 私的には結構
演劇やりたいなって思うんです➡
That may be true...
But personally, I think I'd really like to put on a play.
そっちの音楽系と こっちの演劇で
どっちも見れるとか➡
If the audience can see both your musical performance and our play,
it's a really good deal for them, right?
お客さん的にも
超お得じゃないですか
But if we separate, it would weaken our synergetic effect,
(玉縄)ただセパレートすると
シナジー効果が薄れるし
and it doubles the risk...
ダブルリスクじゃないかなあ
(いろは)ですよね
That's true.
But don't we also have a budget to consider, as well?
でも予算的なのってあるじゃ…
それはみんなで考えていこうよ
Let's all think about that together.
That's what this meeting is for.
そのための会議なんだし
(海浜Ａ)それアグリー
I agree.
Agreed, agreed.
≪(海浜生達)アグリー アグリー
≪(折本)それある！
That's the thing!
Um, can I ask something?
≪(副会長)あの ちょっといいかな
二部構成にすることに
反対の理由って何？
What's your reason for opposing the two-part event structure?
Well, it's not that I oppose it.
≪(玉縄)反対ってわけじゃなくて
ビジョンを共有すればもっと
一体感を出せると思うんだ➡
I just think if we all share our visions, we'll bring a sense of unity to this.
ｲﾒｰｼﾞ戦略の点でも合同ｲﾍﾞﾝﾄの
大枠はﾏｽﾄなんじゃないかな
I think the joint event framework is a must for building a positive image, too.
Is it necessary to do it jointly?
合同でやる必要ってあるか？
もちろん
Of course. By doing it jointly,
合同でやることで
ｸﾞﾙｰﾌﾟｼﾅｼﾞｰを生んで大きなｲﾍﾞﾝﾄを…
we create group synergy and make the event bigger—
シナジーなんてどこにもないし
There's no synergy here at all.
このままだと
大したことできないだろ
And if we keep this up, we'll never achieve anything big.
なのに 何でまだ形にこだわるんだ
So why are you still hung up on the form it takes?
ｺﾝｾﾝｻｽはとれてたし
ｸﾞﾗﾝﾄﾞﾃﾞｻﾞｲﾝの共有もできてたわけで
We've reached a consensus,
and we've shared our ideas for the ground design.
(Ａ･Ｂ･Ｃ)アグリー
≪(折本)それある
I agree.
That's the thing!
That's true.
違うな
You're wrong.
自分はできると
思い上がってたんだよ
I know because I had the conceited idea in my head that I could do it.
だから間違っても
認められなかったんだ
That's why, even though I was wrong, I couldn't admit it.
自分の失敗を
ごまかしたかったんだろう
I guess I wanted to cover up my own mistakes.
そのために策を弄した
言葉を弄した
To do that, I used tricks and words.
I tried to put myself at ease by getting promises out of people.
言質をとって安心しようとした
間違えたとき
誰かのせいにできたら楽だからな
Because when I messed up, it was easier if I could blame it on someone else.
これって単にｺﾐｭﾆｹｰｼｮﾝ不足な
だけな気がするけど
I get the feeling that's just a lack of communication.
一度 ｸｰﾙﾀﾞｳﾝの期間を置いて
もう一度話し合いを重ねれば…
Why don't we take time to cool down and then discuss this again?
I agree.
That's the thing!
(海浜生達)アグリー
ごっこ遊びがしたければ
If you want to play pretend,
よそでやってもらえるかしら？
could you do it elsewhere?
さっきから随分と中身のない
ことばかり言っているけれど
You've been saying all kinds of things that have no meaning.
覚えたての言葉を使って議論の
マネをするお仕事ごっこが
Is it so much fun for you to pretend you're working
by using words you just learned and mimicking a debate?
そんなに楽しい？ あいまいな
言葉で話した気になって
You use vague terms to feel like you spoke up,
分かった気になって
何一つ行動を起こさない
to feel like you understand,
but you take no action whatsoever.
そんなの前に進むわけがないわ
You'll never move forward that way.
何も生み出さない
何も得られない
You won't create anything.
You won't gain anything.
何も与えない ただの偽物
You won't give anyone anything.
You're just a pretender.
ゆきのん…
Yukinon...
これ以上 私達の時間を
奪わないでもらえるかしら
Could you refrain from wasting any more of our time?
無理に一緒にやるより 二回
楽しんでもらえるって思った方が
Uh, wouldn't it be more fun
to let people enjoy the event twice than to force it all into one?
よくない？ それぞれの
学校の個性とかでるじゃん ねえ？
It would show the individuality of both our schools!
Right?
あ はい いいと思います
Uh... Right. I think that sounds great.
ど どうかな？ ねッ？
Wh-What do you think?
(折本)あ うん…
それもあるんじゃない？ ねッ？
Uh, yeah... That could be cool, too.
Right? Right?
(海浜生)うん… その案も…
Yeah...
Well, that makes sense...
That's not a bad idea.
何で二人ともああいうこと
言っちゃいますかね
Why did you two have to say stuff like that?
雰囲気最悪ですよ～
You totally destroyed the mood!
私は間違ったことを
言ったつもりはないけれど
I don't believe anything I said was mistaken.
正論かもしれないですけど
You may have been right, but you could have read the mood a little.
もっと空気を読むっていうか
色々あるじゃないですか
There were other ways to handle that, weren't there?
その男に空気を読むことを
期待するなら無駄よ
If you expect him to read a mood, your hope is in vain.
部室でも文字列しか
読んでいないんだから
Even in our club, he only reads lines of text.
残念だったな
俺クラスの読書家ともなると
Sorry, but no. When you become a reader of my caliber,
行間までちゃんと読んでる
ていうか
you can read between lines, too.
Also, aren't you the one she was just chewing out?
今 怒られてたの お前じゃないの
一色さんは今
正論だと認めたじゃない
But Isshiki-san acknowledged that I was right.
だったら怒られる いわれがないわ
あ それそれ
So there's no reason for me to be chewed out.
Yeah, that. That's exactly why she was chewing you out.
そういうところを怒られてんだよ
話聞け 話
Listen to what she's saying.
あの… 私の話聞いてますか？
二人に言ってるんですよ～
Excuse me!
Were you guys listening to me?
I was talking to both of you!
(比企谷･雪乃)フンッ！
へへへッ
(足音)
はい おごり
Here. My treat.
お おう
Th-Thanks.
イエ～イ
お おう
Yay!
Y-Yeah.
比企谷 ちょっと変わったよね
昔とか超つまんないとか思ってた
You've kinda changed, Hikigaya.
I used to think you were totally boring.
D-Did you?
そ そうか
けど
But if someone looks boring,
it might really be the looker's fault.
人がつまんないのって
結構 見る側が悪いのかもね
でも やっぱ
比企谷と付き合うって無理だな
Still, I don't think I could ever go out with you.
いや 別に今 頼んでないんだけど
Uh, I didn't ask you to do that...
でも 友達としては
ちょっとありかな ウケるし
But...
As friends, I guess it might work.
I mean, you're hilarious.
次 同窓会とかあったら
比企谷も来れば？
If we have a class reunion or anything, why don't you come?
行かねえよ 絶対
だよね ウケる
No. Never.
I figured! That's hilarious!
いや ウケねーから
No, it's not.
(留美)八幡いい いらない
Hachiman, it's okay.
I don't need help. I can handle it by myself.
一人でできる
いや できるっつってもお前
Yeah, maybe you can, but...
いい
It's fine.
でもな 俺の方が
もっと一人でできる
But you know...
I can handle it by myself even better.
何それ バッカみたい
What are you talking about? That's dumb.
なあ お前…
お前じゃない
So you, uh...
I'm not "you."
あん？
留美
I'm Rumi.
あのな 留美
Okay, so, Rumi...
うちの演劇出てみないか？
Want to be in our school's play?
In this bright room
I wait for the thaw you bring
由比ヶ浜さん
クッキーの袋詰め終わった？
Yuigahama-san, did you finish bagging the cookies?
Yeah, I just finished!
うん 今できた～
私もケーキ焼こうか？
Want me to bake a cake, too?
大丈夫よ だから絶対に
手を触れないでね 絶対によ
No need.
So don't touch these, no matter what.
No matter what, okay?
That's kinda mean!
何か言い方がひどい！
Oh, God...
When I wake up, I see a box
We're totally in trouble!
The scenario was well-written.
What's there to be worried about?
None see it as I do
My secretary worked hard on the scenario.
The snow turned my heart a milky white
And, Senpai, you...
Oh, right! I'm gonna go join the others, okay?
which scatters the cold sunlight
Oh, and be sure to check
with the vice president on how to time the ending!
Freezing rain covers my body,
And take care of the cakes for me!
You got it,
and only the distant spring wind may dispel the veil
President.
Take me to a summer garden
where I may grow azalea
I doubt you will
There are no fairy tales full of happiness
I know that all too well
But, you know,
that's where I want to go
I solved the complicated equations
all by myself
I thought it was only natural
and never doubted my actions
But this season will soon come to an end,
and only my shadow on the ground gives me company
あ～ もう
絶対ヤバいですよ
シナリオは よく書けてたし
そんなに心配いらないだろ
Cover this frozen path
シナリオは うちの書記ちゃんが
頑張ってくれましたから
in a storm of flowers
それに先輩が…
and show me the way
あッ そうだ 私もう
みんなのとこ行きますね
There are no perfect crystals made of miracles
あｯ 最後のﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞ 副会長と
確認しておいてくださいね
That is why we come to take
それとケーキの方もよろしくです
one another's hands
了解だ 会長
あッ おかえり～
Welcome back!
Good work today, Yuigahama-san.
お疲れさま 由比ヶ浜さん
Thanks!
ありがとう
えッ 何 どうしたのこれ？
Eh? What?
What's this?
Your Christmas present!
Giving just one person a paper cup would be wasteful.
クリスマスプレゼント
一人だけ紙コップも不経済でしょ
I picked the shape, and Yukinon picked the print.
形は私が選んで 柄はゆきのん
I should've known.
<だろうな>
But I don't have anything for you guys...
いや でも俺
何も用意してないんだけど
You don't need to worry about that.
気にしなくていいわ
ただの紙コップ代わりだもの
It's just a substitute for a paper cup.
Thanks.
ありがとな
どういたしまして
You're welcome!
And for handling my request... uh...
あと 依頼も あ… ありがとな
Thanks. You really saved me.
助かった おかげで無事終わった
It ended in success thanks to you.
まだ依頼は終わっていないでしょ
We haven't finished your request yet.
We said we'd accept your request, didn't we?
あなたの依頼
受けるって言ったじゃない
Uh, yeah... And that just ended, right?
いや だからそれは
もう終わっただろ
何 なぞなぞなの？
What is this, a riddle?
Yes, maybe it is a riddle.
そうね なぞなぞかも
I figured out the answer.
私は分かっちゃったな
ﾋｯｷｰは分かんなくてもいいかもね
Maybe it's okay if you don't, Hikki.
Huh?
ああ？
まあ それはともかくとして
Well, that aside...
まだクリスマスだし
パーティーしようよ
It's still Christmas, so let's have a party!
No, I don't think so.
いや しないだろ
ゆきのんは予定ある？
Do you have plans, Yukinon?
If we're having a party, I'll keep my schedule open.
もしやるなら
空けておくことにするわ
Really? Yay!
ホントに やった！
俺には予定聞かねえのかよ
You're not gonna ask if I have plans?
Or was that a roundabout way of saying I'm not invited?
それとも遠回しに誘ってないって
言いたかったの？
Well, I know you don't have any plans.
だってヒッキー絶対予定ないし…
I want to eat some of the cake you made, Yukinon!
私 ゆきのんのケーキ食べたいな
I made the cake you were eating earlier.
あなたがさっき食べていたｹｰｷ…
If I could be given what I wished for...
<もしも願うものを
与えられるのなら>
If I could have what I wanted,
<ほしいものが もらえるのなら>
then I'd probably never want or wish for anything.
<やはり俺は
何も願わないし 欲しない>
Because the things I received and the things given to me would be fakes
<与えられるものも
もらえるものも>
<それは きっと偽物で>
<いつか失ってしまうから>
that would just disappear someday.
So I think I'll keep wanting.
<だからきっと求め続ける>
(柏手を打つ)
Hey, what should we do about shopping for Yukinon's birthday present?
あのさ ゆきのんの誕生日ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄ
買いにいくの どうする？
Oh... uh...
あ あ～ 明日とか暇か？
Are you free tomorrow?
Y-Yeah, I am...
う うん 空いてるけど
Really? Okay, then tomorrow.
そうか じゃあ 明日…
うん
Okay.
(バイブレーター着信)
あッ 優美子だ
Oh, it's Yumiko!
Yahello, Yumiko!
やっはろー 優美子
ああ ちょっと待ってね
Just a sec, okay?
えっと みんな
これからどうする？
Um, what are you all doing after this?
私は そろそろ帰るわ
人混みは得意ではないし
I'm going to head home.
I don't care for crowds.
えッ でも…
またすぐ学校で会えるじゃない
What? But...
We'll see each other at school again soon, won't we?
うん
Yeah!
≪(小町)あッ いっけな～い➡
Oh, shoot!
小町ったら お守りを
買い忘れてしまいました
I forgot to buy a good luck charm!
それに絵馬も
書き忘れちゃったので
I also forgot to write a wish to hang up,
so I'm gonna run back!
ダッシュで戻りま～す
お守りなら俺も買っとこうかな
Oh, maybe I'll buy a good luck charm, too...
What are you saying, Onii-chan?!
お兄ちゃん 何言ってるの
ごみいちゃんのバカ！
You stupid scum-niichan! You dimwit! You Hachiman!
ボケナス 八幡！
Hachiman isn't an insult!
八幡は悪口じゃねえだろ
雪乃さん では小町はここで
Yukino-san, I'm gonna take off!
クッ クッ クッ…
何だよ
What's with you?
バカ ボケナス 八幡…
Stupid... Dimwit... Hachiman...
<どうやら雪ノ下さんの
罵倒語ディクショナリーが>
It looks like Yukinoshita-san's dictionary of insults was
just updated for the first time in a while.
<久々に更新されたみたいです>
そういや
こっち方面でよかったのか？
Anyway, were you okay heading in this direction?
ええ…
いや 年末年始だから
Yes...
I mean, it's the end of the year,
実家どうしてんのかと思って
ああ
so I thought your family might be doing something.
Oh... I'm not going home this year.
今年は帰ってないわ
特に用があるわけでもないし
I don't have any particular reason to.
それに私は いてもいなくても
大差ないもの
And it won't make much difference whether I'm there or not.
ならいいんじゃねえの
えッ？
Why not go, then?
いてもいなくてもいいって楽だし
If it won't make a difference, that's easier on you.
誰も困らせてないだろ
You wouldn't cause any problems for anyone.
世の中いるだけで
雰囲気悪くするヤツとかいるし
There are people who ruin the atmosphere just by existing, you know.
Is that how you introduce yourself?
それは自己紹介かしら？
そうそう だからなるべく人に
接しないようにしてきたんだよ
Yep. That's why I've always tried to avoid contact with people.
(ドアが開く)
あッ 俺ここだから
Well, this is my stop.
比企谷君
うん？
Hikigaya-kun.
(電車の発車ベル)
今年もよろしく
I look forward to this year.
Super
Lightweight
9g models that don't
let you feel any strain
ふふん 何か頭よさそうじゃない？
Kinda makes me look smart, doesn't it?
メガネ イコール 頭いいって
発想が もう相当頭悪いだろ
Just the idea that glasses equal intelligence makes you pretty stupid.
うるさいバカ
Oh, shut up, jerk!
Blue-Light Blocking
Computer Glasses
≪(陽乃)ありゃ 比企谷君だ
Hey, it's Hikigaya-kun!
陽乃さんと隼人君じゃん
Haruno-san... and Hayato-kun!
やあ
Hey.
Oh, that's right!
≪(陽乃)ああ そっか 雪乃ちゃん
もうすぐ誕生日だもんね それで➡
Yukino-chan's birthday is coming up. So that's why you're here.
にしても二人っきりなんて
相変わらず仲いいな～
Seeing you two alone together, though... Still getting along well, I see.
初めは妹も一緒だったんですけど
My little sister was with us at first,
途中からどっか消えて…
but she took off somewhere along the way.
つーか そっちこそ珍しいですね
Anyway, it's unusual to see you two together, too.
ああ 私達は新年の食事会
Oh, we're here for a New Year's dinner.
昔から両親同士が
親しくしているんだよ
Our parents have always been friends.
俺達は
それに付き合わされてるだけさ
They just made us come along with them.
親なら今 別の
挨拶回りに行ってるよ
My parents are off saying hello to some other people.
私達は それ待ち
ああ なるほど
We're waiting for them.
Ah, I see.
Oh, right!
そうだ
(呼び出し中)
☎もしもし
≪(陽乃)ああ 雪乃ちゃん➡
Hello?
Hi, Yukino-chan! It's your sister!
お姉ちゃんですよ
今から出てこれる？
Can you come out right now?
☎切るわ
あれ いいのかな？
I'm hanging up.
Oh? Are you sure?
☎何？
実はね… はい どうぞ
What is it?
Well, actually...
Here you go!
Wha— Bu—
ちょッ…
あ～ もしもし
☎はあ あきれた
Uh, hello.
I can't believe this.
☎どうして あなたがそこにいるの
What are you doing there?
Um, well, I'm... you know...
えっと それはその 何だ…
☎はあ すぐ行くわ
End Call
I'll be right there.
ゆきの～ん こっち こっち
Yukinon! Over here!
由比ヶ浜さん
あなたも来てたのね
Yuigahama-san... You're here, too?
Uh, yeah, well...
えっと 何ていうか
ヒッキーと買い物してたら
I was shopping with Hikki and we kind of got snagged.
何かつかまっちゃって…
そ そう…
I... I see...
≪(陽乃)雪乃ちゃん おっそ～い
Took you long enough, Yukino-chan!
You've got some nerve, after calling me out here...
いきなり呼び出しておいて
よくもまあ ぬけぬけと…
Now, come on... It looks like Yukino-chan hurried over...
まあまあ 雪乃ちゃんも
だいぶ急いで来たみたいだし…
雪ノ下さんは何飲む？
では 紅茶を
What would you like to drink, Yukinoshita-san?
I'll have black tea.
そろってお茶するのも
久しぶりだね
It's been ages since we all had tea together, huh?
そうだね
Yeah.
Haruno?
(雪乃の母)陽乃
Oh, are you done talking?
≪(陽乃)お話は もういいの？
Yes.
ええ 隼人君
お待たせしちゃってごめんなさい
Hayato-kun, I'm sorry to make you wait.
≪(葉山)いえ みんなのおかげで
退屈しませんでしたから
It's all right. With everyone here, I wasn't bored.
まあ 雪乃 来てくれたのね
よかった
Oh, Yukino, you're here?
I'm glad.
母さん…
Mom...
お友達？
雪乃ちゃんのね
Your friends?
Yukino-chan's.
あら ごめんなさい
Oh, I'm sorry.
隼人君くらいしか 雪乃の
同級生を知らないものだから
I don't know any schoolmates of Yukino's besides Hayato-kun.
これからも
仲良くしてあげてくださいね
Please continue to be good friends to her.
はい
じゃあ そろそろ行きましょうか
We will!
Well, shall we go?
は～い
Sure.
雪乃？
私は…
Yukino.
I...
あなたの
お誕生日祝いでもあるのよ
This is your birthday celebration, as well.
Yukino-chan, don't.
雪乃ちゃん ダメだよ
What the Lights
in Each of Their Hands Illuminate.
♬～
#11     Each and Every Time, Hayama Hayato Lives Up to Expectations.
This must be my true nature.
That's why I could never let go of it.
I just sealed it inside...
...and pretended I didn't see it.
I just wanted to be condemned by the truth.
I wanted someone to see that the idiotic things
I did for others were really for me.
In the eyes of the people looking at me...
That's why I had hope...
that, just maybe, someone would find me.
That someone would see through me.
Truth...
How can you say with certainty that it isn't just an empty delusion?
Does something that's "real" even exist?
(陽乃)これは自分自身の本性
だから結局手放すことができず
ただ封じ込めて
(葉山)見てみないフリをしてきた
(陽乃)ただ自分は
真実によって糾弾されたかった
(葉山)おためごかしのお道化を
見抜いてほしかったのだ
外からこちらを見る瞳によって
(陽乃)だから期待していた
もしかすると自分のことを
見つけてくれるのではないかと
(葉山)
見抜いてくれるのではないかと
真実
(陽乃)それが空虚な妄想でないと
どうして言い切れるのだろう？
(一同)本物なんて
あるのだろうか？